# **VIVIAN JANG**

New York, NY 10002 • 425-389-6292 • vij2@cornell.edu

### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

High-performing senior design product manager with an eye for design with 5 years experience at Microsoft and 8 years experience in semiconductors. Confident in ability to find alignment across cross-functional teams. Comfortable in high-paced environments and self motivated. Committed to team success and continuous personal growth.

## **KEY SKILLS**

- Product Strategy/Roadmap
- Release management
- Stakeholder management
- Backlog management
- Relationship management
- Requirements gathering
- Define and execute against KPI
- Data-driven decision-making
- UX/UI
- AR/VR
- Iterative Design
- Rapid prototyping

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Microsoft

New York, NY and Seattle, WA

September 2021 - Present

Senior Design Product Manager

- Lead UI/UX for Private Preview release of the Mesh for Microsoft Teams app to enable presence and user-centered shared experiences across 2D and 3D endpoints. Defined and executed against 6 KPIs for the Avatar Marketplace to increase community adoption by 30%.
- Defined the Multimodal Interaction roadmap for the HoloLens 3 by gathering quantitative and qualitative insights of eye tracking and hand tracking from in-market users. Led collaboration with an external 3rd party partner to streamline the Speech technology architecture for a consumer-grade HoloLens.
- Co-lead a demo to showcase the future of work and play in the metaverse to Microsoft executives. In a span of 8 weeks, successfully prototyped cloud rendered infinite screens, hyper-real avatars and digital presence in Xbox cloud gaming, resulting in stakeholder buy-in and ensuing launch of 4 productization workstreams of the conceptual technology.

# Technical Program Manager II

January 2019 – September 2021

- Key contributor in the on-time launch of the HoloLens 2; ran daily code flow to burn down 41 critical platform level software issues to improve the quality and reliability of the production software leading up to the launch.
- Laid the foundation for a successful testing strategy by defining software requirements with the DoD and highlighting dependencies of over 1100 test items across 12 different systems groups.
- Improved HoloLens 2 device standby performance of 7 KPIs by an average of 6% by leading cross-functional deep dive investigations into failing device sessions and telemetry and submitting 23 pull requests in software updates.

#### **Texas Instruments**

Munich, Germany and Dallas, TX

Project Manager

May 2017 - November 2018

- Managed end to end development of a high precision analog product line from microchip design to high volume production by delivering risk mitigation strategies and executing against 13 manufacturing quality OKRs.
- Partnered with Product Management, Engineering, Operations and Manufacturing to deliver 7 projects on-time and under budget, ultimately delivering \$41M in divisional annual revenue.

Quality Lead

March 2016 – May 2017

- Served as people manager of five engineers across EMEA and Asia.
- Innovated and championed improvements across 7 manufacturing sites and 26 new product development initiatives while balancing key customer requirements with business unit priorities and operational efficiency.

Quality Engineer

August 2010 - March 2016

- Performed root cause failure analysis of over 300 faulty analog integrated circuits and presented investigation results to customers to bring clarity to the investigation process and resolution.
- Repaired relationships with key automotive customers and restored \$200M+ in future business by taking ownership of past mistakes on behalf of the company and implementing changes in internal processes to ensure investigation results were communicated in a timely, thorough manner.
- Authored a white paper and presented at ISTFA (International Symposium for Testing and Failure Analysis) 2014 about the Physical Isolation of a Die in a Stacked-Die Configuration.

## **EDUCATION**

**Cornell University,** Ithaca, NY Bachelor of Science, Electrical and Computer Engineering